<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Yajie Yan</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Yajie Yan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Voxel Core: Computing Medial Axes in 3D</title>
      <link>/project/voxelcore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/voxelcore/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a novel algorithm for computing the medial axes of 3D shapes. We make the observation that the medial axis of a voxel shape can be simply yet faithfully approximated by the interior Voronoi diagram of the boundary vertices, which we call the voxel core. We further show that voxel cores can approximate the medial axes of any smooth shape with homotopy equivalence and geometric convergence. These insights motivate an algorithm that is simple, efficient, numerically stable, and equipped with theoretical guarantees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erosion Thickness: Simplifying Medial Axes in 3D</title>
      <link>/project/et/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 23:22:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/et/</guid>
      <description>Abstract While playing a fundamental role in shape understanding, the medial axis is known to be sensitive to small boundary perturbations. Methods for pruning the medial axis are usually guided by some measure of significance. The majority of significance measures over the medial axes of 3D shapes are locally defined and hence unable to capture the scale of features. We introduce a global significance measure that generalizes in 3D the classical Erosion Thickness (ET) measure over the medial axes of 2D shapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voxelcore Readme</title>
      <link>/project/voxelcore-readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 19:10:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/voxelcore-readme/</guid>
      <description>Pipeline Figure 1. Pipeline of generating medial axis using voxelcore program. Users first prepare their datasets into dense volumes or sparse volumes, and then run voxelcore to produce medial axes. Optionally the medial axes can be further simplified using another tightly related tool called Erosion Thickness. Please see its project page for details. Usually the user is in pocession of a digital shape that&amp;rsquo;s either represented as a volume by a set of images, or as a surface by a triangular mesh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust medial axis computation and regularization</title>
      <link>/project/ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 18:02:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ma/</guid>
      <description>This project presents a robust medial axis generation pipeline. It consists of two works:
 Voxel Core: Efficient, robust, and provably good approximation of 3D medial axes. See readme Erosion thickness on medial axes of 3D shapes  (details coming soon&amp;hellip;)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>